# Madrid, Spain 19/04/1995

nic.tap95@gmail.com nicolastapiasanz.github.io github.com/nicolastapiasanz

+34 686 433 376

# Nicolás Tapia Sanz

# **Videogame & Tool Programmer**

Graduated in Videogames Design & Development Degree at ESNE University specialized in programming. Passionate of video games, music and all audiovisual stuff. I have knowledges in programming, design and videogames production. I have worked in several videogames getting involved to the fullest and always trying to take them as far as possible. I have presented my last game, Dead Science, in some of the biggest videogames events of Spain to publishers. Also, I have worked in some research projects for simulation in VR and Al.

#### **ACADEMIC EDUCATION**

**2015 - 2019: Videogames Design & Development Degree**, ESNE (Madrid, Spain) **Programming Specialization** 

4th year modules included:

- Advanced 3D Animation (9.65)
- Digital Post-Production (9.60)
- Final Project Degree (9)
- Production II (9)
- Graphics Engines and Plugins (8.85)
- Artificial Intelligence II (8.43)

2nd year modules included:

- Web Videogames Design & Development (10)
- Object-oriented Programming (9.15)
- Visual Programming for Videogames (9)
- Animations & Scripting (8.40)
- Scripts & Storyboarding (8)

3rd year modules included:

- Externships (10)
- Artificial Intelligence (10)
- Operating Environments & Platforms (9.80)
- 3D Animation (9.40)
- Videogames Design: Levels (9.25)
- Videogames Production I (9)
- Videogames Audio (9)

1st year modules included:

- Videogames Technology (10)
- Introduction to the Creative Process (10)
- Basics of Databases (9.1)
- Fundamentals of Programming I (9)
- Programming II (9)

2013 - 2015: Computing Engineer Degree, Universidad Complutense de Madrid (Madrid, Spain) (Not finished)

2011 - 2013: Spanish Bachillerato (A Level), La Salle (Burgos, Spain) (Technology Science Branch)

#### **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

Programming Languages Professional Knowledge: C# / .NET, C++, Blueprints, HTML, CSS

Basic Knowledge: OpenGL, Java, Javascript, Maxscript, SQL

Videogames Engines Unity Engine, Unreal Engine 4, Construct 3, PlayStation 4 DevKit

Physics Engines PhysX, Bullet, Box2D

Graphics CG, HLSL, GLSL

Other SFML, SDL2, OOP, Visual Studio, Android Studio, VR, AR, GIT, Scrum

Languages Spanish: Native Language

English: Fluent

# PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

August 2020 - Current: Unity Developer Specialist - Lurtis Rules (Half Trading Day) (Teleworking - Burgos, Spain)

Teleworking as Junior Programmer in Lurtis Rules with a half trading day. Development of 3D Tools for Engineering and Architecture with Unity in C# and .NET.

December 2019 - July 2020: Junior Programmer - Lurtis Rules (Half Trading Day) (Teleworking - Burgos, Spain)

Teleworking as Junior Programmer in Lurtis Rules with a half trading day. Development of 3D Tools for Engineering and Architecture with Unity in C# and .NET.

# July 2019: Virtual Reality Master Class Lecturer / Teacher- ESNE (Madrid, Spain)

Virtual Reality Master Class Teacher in the Videogames Design and Development degree in Digital Post-production subject for the Programming branch students. I taught the basics of virtual reality, existing hardware and its use in engines such as Unity and Unreal Engine 4.

## July 2019: Videogames Camp Lecturer / Teacher - ESNE (Madrid, Spain)

Videogames Urban Summer Camp for students between 16-18. Divided in two groups: Basic and Advanced. I taught the basic principles of programming videogames in Construct and Unity respectively to each group. We developed different Top Down, Scroll and Infinite Runner games in 2D.

## February 2019 - September 2019: Simulation Programmer - ESNE (Madrid, Spain)

A simulation of population masses in central Madrid for the analysis of the citizen security system. Programmed in Unity and C#. In collaboration with Lenovo and the Madrid City Council.

## December 2017 - November 2018: VR Programmer - Observatorio Español del Diseño (OED) (Madrid, Spain)

Development of a VR research project about pedestrians behaviour in situations of running over cars. Simulations of real outrages of vehicles in Madrid. Developed in Unity Engine and C# with Lenovo Explorer headset and HTC Vive Pro.

## November 2016 - December 2016: QA Tester - TOUCHVIE (Madrid, Spain)

I tested a second screen app of movies and series called Dive for Android devices looking for concrete bugs.

### July 2016 - September 2016: Game Designer Support - Gammera Nest (Madrid, Spain)

I worked at the design and narrative department for the PS4 game Nubla 2.

## **OTHER EXPERIENCE**

February 2017 - July 2019: Game Producer, Designer, Programmer, BizDev & PR - Unknown Outcome (Madrid, Spain)

University Videogames Studio. We worked in two games: *Dead Science*, a first person exploration and puzzles game for PC platform and consoles developed in Unreal Engine 4; and *Emergency Room*, a 3D overhead game for PC platform and consoles developed in Unity. This project was in the PlayStation First program.

#### 2017, 2018 & 2019: Support Staff at ESNE Stand in AULA Event- ESNE (Madrid, Spain)

# May 2018: Best Audio Award at #ESNEGameJamon inLudum Dare 41 with "Warren Of Love" (Madrid, Spain) University PC Videogame developed at Ludum Dare 41. Available at Itch.io.

### December 2016 - November 2017: Mechanics & Tools Programmer - Beware The Dev (Madrid, Spain)

University Videogames Studio. Improvements on game designers workflow with C# in Unity Engine.

#### April 2017 - May 2017: PlayStation First Program - Sony & ESNE (Madrid, Spain)

University Program developed by Sony to learn how to compile and make videogames with a PS4 DevKit.

# February 2016 - June 2016: Game Producer, Designer & Programmer - Just Dream (Madrid, Spain)

University Videogame development. Mobile game available at Play Store.

#### February 2015 - May 2015: Game Producer, Programmer & Designer - Gravity Cube (Madrid, Spain)

The first videogame I developed on my own. Mobile game available at Play Store.

## **HOBBIES AND INTERESTS**

Videogames	Jak & Daxter Saga, God Of War,, Age Of Empires, The Last Of Us, Bloodborne
Sports	Skateboarding, Surfing, Trekking
Other	Movies, Series, Music, Fantasy Books, Electric Guitar
Jams	Ludum Dare, GameJamOn